我爱你们，漂亮的人们知道，在过去的几节课里，你们做了这么多关于文件的事情。
Love you beautiful people know in the last few lectures you've been doing so much stuff with files.
您已经掌握了如何创建它们、移动它们、复制它们、删除它们、粘贴它们、重命名它们
You've been you've had how to create them move them around copy them delete them paste them rename them
去寻找他们。
and search for them.
还有更多。
And so much more.
好的。
OK.
所有操作都是从命令行进行的。
All from the command line.
但是，尽管我们现在可以在很大程度上处理文件，但我们还没有真正了解如何快速
But even though we can now manipulate files on a grand level we haven't really seen how to take a quick
看一看里面有什么，还可以操纵它们的内容。
peek at what's inside them and manipulate their contents yet.
好了，这就是接下来的几个视频的目的，接下来的几个视频将学习五个
Well that's what these next few videos are for over the next few videos are going to be learning five
允许您操作文件内容的新命令。
new commands that will allow you to manipulate file contents.
这就是读取文件、反转文件甚至将文件粘合在一起的内容
So this is stuff such as reading files reversing files and even sticking files together as well as reading
它们在一些寻呼程序中。
them in some paging programs.
因此，这样做可以让您从命令行完成大部分工作，而不需要
So what this is can allow you to do is to get most of your work done from the command line without ever
必须开放外部编辑器，这将是一个巨大的生产力提升，而且
having to need to open up external editors which is going to be a massive productivity boost and it's
将帮助您保持在整个命令行工作过程生态系统中。
going to help you keep you inside the whole command line work process ecosystem.
所以这将会是非常非常棒的你。
So this is going to be very very you.
所以这就像是在那一分钟丢失了一块，在它之后或者在下一个视频结束之后，你就是
So it's kind of like a missing piece at the minute and after it or after the end of the next video you're
我将不得不对合并后的文件内容执行一大堆有用的功能
going to have to perform a whole bunch of useful functions on the contents of files which when combined
根据您对文件整体操作的了解，您将了解服务器场
with what you know about manipulating files in their entirety is going to make you you know the farm
操纵大师。
manipulation master.
所以我们就直接跳进去吧。
So let's just go ahead and jump right into it.
好的。
OK.
我们要看的第一个命令是cat命令。
So the first command that we're going to take a look at is the cat command.
现在你还记得我之前跟你说的那些厨房笑话吗？
Now do you remember those kitchen jokes that I was talking to you about earlier.
好了，米罗，现在你实际上已经看到盖子以前戴上了。
Well mirro So now you've actually seen the cap come on before.
所以这将是一次相当不错的复习。
So this will be a rather nice refresher.
好的，你可以在我们的桌面上看到，我们有几个文件。
OK so you can see here on our desktop we've got a few files.
我们得到了4 1 4 2 5 3 4 4和4 5DirectXT。
We got 4 1 4 2 5 3 4 4 and 4 5 directx T.
那么让我们来看看第一个文件里面有什么。
So let's take a look at what's inside the first file.
但是，我们不会打开它，而是要查看我们的终端，看看文件中有什么。
But instead of opening it we're going to look in our terminal to see what's inside the file.
好的。
OK.
所以，如果我们输入cat，然后将其放到桌面上，不是吗？
So if we type cat and then follow on it to be on the desktop don't I.
所以我将在屏幕上更改桌面，然后键入cat并将一条文本发送给我。
So I'll change the desktop I the screen and then type cat and file one text me.
好的，我想按回车键。
OK I want to press enter.
我们将看到该文件的内容已写入标准输出。
We'll see that the contents of the file have been written to standard output.
我们可以看到该文件包含单词Hello。
And we can see that the file contains the word Hello.
现在，如果我按下，如果我，你知道，双击它，然后以图形方式打开它，我们可以看到，是的，所有这些
Now if I press if I you know double click that and open that graphically we can see that yes all that
文件包含的是单词Hello。
file contains is the word Hello.
好的。
OK.
因此，使用该命令，我们成功地将文件内容打印到标准输出OK。
So using the command we managed to get the contents of the file printed to standard output OK.
所以让我们试着看看第二个会有什么结果。
So let's try and see what's in for number two.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我们对它做cat文件，我们可以看到单词在里面。
So if we do cat file to that takes t we can see the word there is inside.
我想你可以想象这件事会发展到什么地步。
I guess you can imagine where this is going right.
所以如果我赌3，你就会看到4，4。
So if I go for three it says you see 4 4.
上面写着很漂亮，我打赌我们都能猜到第五名会是什么。
It says beautiful and I bet we can all guess what's in for number five.
所以如果我按5，它会说人们没事。
So if I press 5 It says people are OK.
所以如果你把下面所有的文件放在一起，它会说你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
So if you put all the follow files together it says hello there you beautiful people.
真是太巧了。
Well what a coincidence.
我想知道这是怎么回事。
I wonder how that happened.
因此，实际上您可以使用Capcom将文件粘合在一起。
So in fact you can actually use the Capcom and to stick files together.
好的。
OK.
实际上通常是这样的，cat是单词conatenates的缩写，这是一个花哨的词
And that's actually usually what it's for cat is short for the word concatenates which is a fancy word
因为他们团结在一起。
for sticking together.
好的。
OK.
所以cat所做的就是将所有输入文件粘合在一起，然后将粘合在一起的内容传递给
So what cat does is stick together all of the input files and then pass that stick together stuff to
标准输出。
standard output.
好的，如果我们这样做，屏幕上，如果我们做猫下降1.60，Faltu，那就是下降3.50，下降60
OK so if we do OK the screen if we do cat fall 1.60 Faltu that takes the fall 3.50 fall for that 60
并将5.6磁带归档，然后按Enter键。
and file 5.6 tape and press enter.
你可以看到，你们这些漂亮的人，你们好，是通过把五千人粘在一起而形成的。
You can see that hello there you beautiful people has been made by sticking together the five thousand
已打印到我们的标准输出中。
that has been printed to our standard output.
但我们当然可以将其重定向到桌面上名为Beautiful Dotty XTi的新文件，我们可以
But we can of course redirect this to a new file called Beautiful Dotty XTi on our desktop which we
请参见已在此处创建。
see has been created here.
当我们打开的时候，我们现在看到我们有一个新的文件，它说你好，美丽的人们
And when we open we now see that we've got a new file that says hello there beautiful people that has
是通过将其他五个文件粘合在一起而创建的。
been created by sticking together five other files.
现在我们可以看到，这个命令行上的洞很长，对吧。
Now we can actually see the holes in this command line here is quite long right.
实际上，我们可以使用通配符知识来简化这一过程。
What we can actually simplify that using our knowledge of wildcards.
因此，CAS不再是1.60，而是下跌了2.6，下跌了3.6，下跌了4.6，下跌了5，5.6。
So instead of having CAS for 1.60 fell 2.6 fall 3.6 for 4.6 and 5 5.6.
理想情况下，您只需将像这只猫这样的通配符组合在一起，将一到五个文本组合成一个漂亮的服务器
You can just use a wildcard like this cat together for one to five text into a beautiful server ideally
很漂亮，很好吃，而且不是外卡。
beautiful that tasty and not wild card.
它又被创建了，我们可以在这里看到，但是我们得到了完全相同的结果。
And it's been created again and we can see here but yet we get exactly the same result.
你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello there you beautiful people.
但打字要少得多。
But a lot less typing.
所以现在这已经很酷了。
So that's pretty cool right now.
来吧，当您想像这样将文件粘合在一起时，它显然对粘合文本文件很有用
Come on when you want to stick files together like this it's useful for sticking to the text files obviously
但它在处理Odeo或MP3文件时可能非常有用。
but it can be very useful when working with Odeo or MP 3 files for example.
所以如果你可以有多个不同的单MP，三个文件，你知道不同的歌曲，例如
So if you can have multiple different single MP three files you know different songs for example but
您实际上可以将它们连接在一起，将这些不同的文件粘贴在一起以创建一个长文件
you can actually concatenate them together stick these different files together to create one long file
里面有所有的音乐。
that has all the music in it.
所以这是相当史诗般的。
So that's pretty epic.
因此，cat命令用于将文件粘合在一起。
So the cat command is used to stick files together.
实际上，如果你想要的话，只要读一下文件的内容，我们就可以做CAT了。
Actually if you want just read the contents of a file so we can just do cat.
漂亮的圆点文字。
Beautiful dot text.
所以Cat美化了文本，我们可以看到任何文件的内容，这真的很有用。
So Cat beautiful that text and we can see the contents of any of any file which is really really useful.
但是我想了解的另一个命令是TAC命令。
But another command that I want to take a look at is the TAC command.
所以让我把这里的屏幕清理一下。
So let me just clear the screen here.
因此，TAC命令只是向后拼写为cat，它用于反转作为
So the TAC command is just cat spelled backwards and it's used to reverse whatever it receives as an
输入。
input.
因此，如果我们通过回显创建一个名为Alpha TXI的文件，让我们假设abc为我们的保真度xt，我们将
So if we make a file called Alpha TXI by echoing let's say ABC to our fidelity x t and we're going to
另外，将DPF回显到Alpha，并注意我们在这里获得aros的方式，因为我们要将
also echo DPF to Alpha and notice the way that we've got to Aros here because we're going to append
复制到同一个文件，而不是覆盖它。
to the same file rather than overwrite it.
好的，现在如果我按字母顺序看，我们一行有abc，另一行有dpf。
OK so now if I look in alphabetically we've got ABC on one line and DPF on another.
好的，如果我们读取文件，我们使用cat和Sue cat来读取文件，按照字母顺序，我们得到ABC，然后是D
OK so if we read the file we read the file using cat with Sue cat alphabetically we get ABC then D E
F.
好的。
OK.
但我会看看如果我们用Tack来读会发生什么。
But I'll see what happens if we read it using tack.
所以我们用ptak代替cat来读它，ptak是宠物猫，拼写倒过来，我们现在看到我们
So instead of cat we read it using Ptak which is the pet cat spelled backwards and we see now that we
先取d f，然后取abc。
get d f then ABC.
因此您可以看到，TAC命令实际上反向读取了整个文件，但是离开了该文件。
So you can see that the TAC command actually reads the whole file in reverse but leaves the file.
这些行是一样的，所以它只是先写最后一行，然后最后写第一行。
The lines the same so it just wrote the last line first and then the first line last.
是的，但是它不影响每行的任何文本。
Right but it didn't affect any text on each line.
因此，如果我们将各种不同的文件放在一起，使用CATS将文件设置为4：59，如果我们这样做的话
So if we stick together and the various different files here the file to 4:59 using cats if we do file
万美元到5.60美元，你看，我们在那里得到了产量。
wan to $5.60 you see that we get the output there.
但现在我想让你们想一想如果我们发动攻击会发生什么。
But now I want you to think what might happen if we pipe that into attack.
好的。
OK.
现在，TAC将按行反转文件，以便首先打印最后一行，然后打印第一行
Now TAC will reverse the file line wise so the last line will be printed first and the first line will
最后打印。
be printed last.
你觉得这会有什么结果。
So what do you think might come out of this.
花几秒钟，我的意思是想一想。
Take a couple of seconds I mean think about it.
所以可能会发生的是最后一句话，那就是以人为本，第一句话就会出现
So what might happen is the last line which is people would come first and the first line would come
最后，可能会出现的是那里的人都很漂亮。
last so what might come out is people beautiful you there.
你好。
Hello.
就像我说的，看一下。
Like I said Have a look.
给你，是的，那里的人都很漂亮。
There you go yeah people beautiful you there.
你好。
Hello.
因此，可以将TAC命令视为垂直反转文件。
So think of the TAC command as reversing a file vertically.
好的。
OK.
所以它只是把它颠倒过来。
So it just flips it upside down.
它不会影响任何一条线路。
It doesn't affect any of the lines.
它只是把它颠倒过来。
It just flips it upside down.
当然，因为所有这些都打印到标准输出，所以您当然可以将其重定向到
And of course because this is all being printed to standard output you can of course redirect it into
文件名为Reverted。
the file called reversed.
xti，这里是他的反向文本。
XTi And here we are his reverse text.
当我们打开时，我们看到我们已经将输出保存在该文件中。
When we open up we see that we've saved the output in that file.
因此，可以使用tuck命令的好处是，如果我们再举一个
So the good thing about the tuck command where it can be used is again if we take the example of an
MP3文件我不知道你有没有在网上看过那些视频，人们会说，哎呀，看这首歌是怎么回事
MP3 files I don't know if you've ever seen those videos online where people say aw look what the song
说当它向后播放时，就像你知道的那样，他们试图说它有一些隐藏的信息在
says when it's played backwards and like you know they try to say it's got some hidden messages in the
文件。
file.
也许你看过那些视频。
Maybe you've seen those videos.
嗯，也许它们是使用TAX命令创建的，因为如果您运行一个MP3，通过
Well maybe they were made using the tax command because if you run an MP 3 fall through through the
如果我做了一些事情，比如把我父亲钉在P3里，然后把它保存到另一个我反向的文件中，那么我就会纳税几个月
tax months if I did something like tack my father in P3 and save that into another my reversed file
计时p 3，然后是这个文件。
time p 3 then this file.
这里的这首歌是同一首歌，只是倒放了一下。
This one here will be the same song but played backwards.
就像我说的，如果你愿意，可能会试一试。
Like I said something to potentially give a go if if if you would like.
好的，这就是大头针。
OK so that's the tack.
来吧，高明会垂直翻转文件。
Come on the Takamine will reverse files vertically.
还有一个我想看的，叫做REV命令。
There's one other that I want to look at which is called the Rev command.
因此，该命令允许您反转每行上的内容。
So the command allows you to reverse the content on each line.
所以，如果我清空屏幕，好的，我们再把各种不同的文件剪切在一起，我们会得到你好，美丽的你
So if I clear the screen OK and we cut together the various different files again we get hello you beautiful
人民。
people.
但是如果我把它输入REV命令，好的。
But if I pipe that into the Rev command OK.
看看这里发生了什么。
Look what happens here.
它仍然在说，如果你能读懂它，它仍然会说，你好，漂亮的人，所以线条是垂直的
It's still saying if you can read it it still says hello there beautiful people so the lines are vertically
它们是一样的，但是水平方向是相反的，所以每一行的最后一个字母，这里是O。
the same but horizontally they've been reverse so the last letter of each line so here is the O.
现在已经成为第一个字母。
Has now become the first letter.
你知道它是沿着线颠倒的，但是每条线的顺序是一样的。
And you know it's reverse them along the lines but the order of each line is the same.
如果这是有意义的，如果我们放上攻击命令，你可以看到人是第一行
If that makes sense if we if we put the the attack command you can see that people is the first line
而这里的人是最后一行，但是字母已经颠倒了。
whereas here people is the last line but the letters have been reversed.
好的。
OK.
因此，这就是您可以将ref和tac tac反转看作垂直的文件，而rev反转
So this is the way you can think of ref and tac tac reverse as a file vertically and rev reverses a
横向归档。
file horizontally.
好的。
OK.
现在，您可以通过管道将文件同时传送到这两个文件，从而真正地将它们混杂在一起。
Now you can really jumble up files by piping it through both of them.
所以如果我把它穿过塔克，它会垂直反转。
So if I pipe it through Takk it's going to reverse vertically.
但是如果我也通过Rev管道，你现在会得到一个垂直反转和水平反转的
But then if I pipe that also through Rev you've now got a vertically reversed and horizontally reversed
着火，如果你觉得这特别有用的话，这是一个把东西弄乱的好方法。
fire which is a good way of jumbling up stuff if you ever find that particularly useful.
不过，为了方便起见，只需将大头针想象为在列中垂直反转PHIP，而您
But yet just to make it easier just think of tack as reversing phials vertically in columns and you
可以将Rev看作是横跨各行的反向下落。
can think of Rev as reversing falls horizontally across the rows.
所以所有这些命令，不管是猫，还是Takk，还是Be，你知道，它们所做的一切
So all of these commands whether it be cats or it be Takk or a be you know Rev all they're doing is
他们获取一个文件，将其读入标准输入，进行一些处理，然后您知道，只是随地吐痰
they are taking a file reading it into standard input doing some processing and then you know just spitting
将输出转换为标准输出。
that the output to standard output.
就像我说的，它们是一种很好的步行方式，这是阅读文件的一种很好的方式，你知道其他的都是
Like I said they're a good way walk that is a good way of reading files and you know the others are
把东西弄得乱七八糟的好方法。
a good way of jumbling up stuff.
但问题是，当您像这样将文件读取到终端时，如果文件特别长，它可能会
But the problem is when you read files to the terminal like this if a file is particularly long it can
阅读器阻塞了你的屏幕，它不是很有用，你会发现自己滚动了很长很长的一段路。
readers clog up your screen and it's not very useful and you find yourself scrolling a long long way.
因此，如果我们尝试查找一个相当大的文件，例如，如果我们说，让我们使用find命令search
So if we try to find a file that's quite large so if we say for example let's use the find command search
我们的系统最大深度是4米。
our system up to let's say a maximum depth of four.
对于任何配置文件或以.com结尾的名称，我们都会做得太过火。
We're going to go too far for any configuration files or a name that ends in dot com.
以及比方说超过20千字节的大小。
And the size that lets say over 20 kilobytes.
好的，所以我们是，我们只有两个，真的只有两个。
OK so we are we only get we only get two really.
但这里有一家叫警察浏览网站。
But there's one here called cops browes dot com.
这与类似的打印服务有关。
And this is to do with like printing services.
显然这是一个相当大的文件。
And it's apparently a lot rather large file.
所以如果我复制它。
So if I copy it.
收到，试着接住它。
Copy that and try to catch it.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我试着把它切开。
So if I try to cut that it up.
所以如果我试着盖上盖子然后按Enter，你就会看到它就在那里发生了。
So you see it just happened right there if I try to cap that and press enter.
你看，我们刚刚被击落了。
You see that we've just shot down.
她让他出轨了。
She put him out of lines.
你现在能看到了吗。
Can you see now.
如果我想看一看，结果一直滚动到这里，那就不太好了
If I wanted to have a look at it and I ended up scrolling all the way through here it's not very good
正确的。
right.
因此，当您在命令行上处理内容时，这是一个问题，而我们需要一个更优雅的解决方案
So that's a problem when you're dealing with stuff on the command line and we want a more elegant solution
涉及处理相对较大的文件。
to dealing with relatively large files.
有时候你知道，如果我，如果我只是想读出，也许我不想要整个农场，也许
And sometimes you know if I if I just wanted to read out of how maybe I don't want all of the farm maybe
只想要它的某个片段，也许我只想要前10行或后10行之类的
only want a certain snippet of it maybe I only want the top 10 lines or the bottom 10 lines or something
就像这样。
like that.
我们需要有一种更好的方式来处理命令行上的文件内容。
And we need to have a better way of being able to deal with file contents on the command line.
综上所述，我们将在下一个视频中介绍的内容，但在总结这个视频时，我们
So in summary So what we're going to be covering in the next video but in summary of this video we've
看到它们不能来，可以用来实际读出文件。
seen that they can't come and can be used to actually read out files.
如果我在我们的桌面上看起来很美，如果我读到他实际上可以读出有多美，如果我们
If I look beautiful on our desktop if I read how beautiful that he actually can read that out if we
想要垂直反转文件，我们可以使用Takk如果我们想要水平反转文件，我们可以使用
want to reverse files vertically we can use Takk if we want to reverse files horizontally we can use
Rev，但不管是哪种方式，所有这些都是他们正在做的，他们只是在读取文件内容
Rev and but all either way all of these are what they're doing is they are just reading the files content
并输出标准输出，然后当然可以通过管道将其传递到其他命令中
and spitting out the standard output where you can then of course pipe it into other commands to do
处理过程。
the processing.
好的。
OK.
或者您知道，当您在命令行上工作时，如果您只是想快速查看文件中的内容
Or you know while you're working on the command line if you just want to see quickly what's in a file
您可以只使用CAT命令，然后快速查看并获取
you can just you can just use cats come at the cat command and then see that really quickly and get
继续你在做的事。
on with what you were doing.
好的。
OK.
现在我们来看一下cat tack和ref命令，但在下一个视频中，我们将使用
So there we are though does the cat tack and ref commands but in the next video we're going to take
A看看你如何提升这种能力来做更复杂的事情，所以我要把这段视频
a look at how you can level up this ability to do more sophisticated things so I'll break the video
在这里，我们将在下一个视频中看到你。
here and see you in the next video.